

## Nicolas solerieu

contact@solerieu-nicolas.fr (+33) 7 86 17 97 49

**Current location** Auvergne, France Relocation available

I'm a 22 years old designer from France. I design & build digital products for brands and services since 2012.

I have been itching for an environment change for a few months; something that challenges and inspires a bit more than my current office gig. If you can help me in my quest, feel free to send me a mail.

## **SELECTED EXPERIENCE**

January 2014 -Today

IRIS INTERACTIVE, Le Puy

Web / Front end designer

Designed and built several websites with wordpress and many jquery plugins. Published UI for major application mostly in automobile industry. I created ads and banners from idea to release on the web. I took part in the design process of large scale applications (mostly UX, UI, HTML prototyping).

April 2012 -Today

FREELANCE, Chambéry

Web & UI Designer

Initialy specialized in the design of website, I designed and coded few wordpress powered websites. Then I started doing some application and interaction design for clients all over the world. I like freelance jobs because it allow me to try new technologies and talk with new interesting people.

**EDUCATION** 

July 2012 -August 2013 **BACHELOR'S DEGREE** 

Specialties: Online multimedia design

School: IUT du Puy-en-Velay (43, haute-loire, FR)

Sept 2010 -June 2012

**ASSOCIATE DEGREE** 

Specialties: Multimedia creation and networking School: IUT de Chambéry (73, haute-savoie, FR)

**PERSONAL** 

Born:

April 25, 1992

Languages:

French (native), English (good)

Software:

Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Indesign, sketch basics, Blender basics, Coda

Technical skills:

Working knowledge of php/html/css and Javascript.

Responsive, adaptive design and thorought understanding of screen resolution and

plateform compatibility issues.

Specialties:

Visual design, User interface design, Interaction design, Concepting/prototyping,

Information architecture, Web design, visual identity systems

Hobbies:

Running, hiking and travelling

## **MOTIVATION AND DESIGN VISION**

Visual design is not art, it's a science. I'm a technician, not an artist. Design is about function, it's a solution for a task. I also consider design as a vector for people to gather around an idea, a product. I'm looking for an opportunity to apply my design and language skills in an international environment to perfect my definition of "design".